Guide to the Joan Weiss Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Joan Weiss papers
1970-2017
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6279
6279-001
Weiss, Joan$c(Labor activist)
3.02 cubic feet (3 boxes) plus 1 oversize vertical file
Collection consists of worksheets, pamphlets, buttons, and guides related to employee unions and programs
Joan Weiss is a labor activist, union member, and union leader. Weiss worked for the M.L. King County Labor Council Worker's Center before the program was ended. Weiss was also a member and business agent for the Classified Staff Association 925 at the University of Washington. That local union is now part of Service Employees International Union, Local 925.
Materials from Weiss work for the M.L. King County Labor Council Worker's Center as well as the Classified Staff Association 925 at the University of Washington. Common Sense Economics training materials from classes that Bill Fletcher, Jr. taught in Seattle in the early 1990s. Posters, buttons, and stickers from various labor and political causes Weiss was a part of or a supporter. It also includes training materials, ephemera, and notes relating to Weiss' membership in SEIU 925 and being a member of the Service Employees International Union, and the AFL-CIO.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
No restrictions on access.
Donated by Joan Weiss.
Weiss, Joan$c(Labor activist)$vArchives; American Federation of Labor$vArchives; AFL-CIO$vArchives; AFL-CIO.$bKing County Labor Council of Washington.$bWorkers Center$vArchives; Service Employees International Union$vArchives; Service Employees International Union.$bLocal 925$vArchives; Labor$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor unions$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor movement$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor union locals$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Labor union members$zWashington (State)$zSeattle; Records (Documents); Course materials; Conference materials; Posters; Ephemera; $i Container of (work): $a Fletcher, Bill,$cJr. $t Common sense economics; $i Container of (work): $a AFL-CIO. $t AFL-CIO publication; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Businesses and Corporations; Civil Activism; Political Campaigns
- [Labor Stickers, Flyers, Programs, Pin], approximately 1992, 2001-2005, 2012 (Box-folder 1/1)
- AFL Common Sense Economics, 1997 March 26 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Memo Training, 1996 November (Box-folder 1/3)
- [AFL-CIO Publications], 1980-1981, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 1/4)
- WSLC Organizing Conference (Workshop by Emily), 1996 May (Box-folder 1/5)
- AFL Social Security, 1998 (Box-folder 1/6)
- WALC Strikes, Strategy, Boeing Strike, 1996 (Box-folder 1/7)
- [AFL-CIO Organizing for Change Report], 1997 (Box-folder 1/8)
- [Work Style Indicators], 1990, 1996 (Box-folder 1/9)
- AFL-CIO Common Sense Economics Study Group Manual [1 of 2], 1996 (Box-folder 1/10)
- AFL-CIO Common Sense Economics Study Group Manual [2 of 2], 1996 (Box-folder 1/11)
- Various Workforce Buttons, unknown (Box-folder 1/12)
- Common Sense Economics "The Rap Script for trainers" [1 of 2], 2000-2002 (Box-folder 1/13)
- Common Sense Economics "The Rap Script for trainers" [2 of 2], 2000-2002 (Box-folder 1/14)
- Common Sense "Campaign for Global Fairness", 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1/15)
- Restoring every worker's right to a Voice @ Work, Unknown (Box-folder 1/16)
- Union Cities Leadership Retreat AFL-CIO/UALE, 2003 April (Box-folder 1/17)
- Building a Strong Grassroots Union Movement, 2003 April 9-13 (Box-folder 1/18)
- Teamsters Fighting for the Future, 1997 (Box-folder 1/19)
- Organizing Institute, 1997 (Box-folder 1/20)
- Labor Education and Research Center - University of Oregon, 1997 (Box-folder 1/21)
- Building Workforce Partnerships Conference/Los Angeles, 2008 June (Box-folder 2/1)
- Which Way Labor? Rebuilding the Labor Movement and Labor Education, 2006 May 17-19 (Box-folder 2/2)
- Education Statistics - The Real World, Unknown (Box-folder 2/3)
- Building Workforce Partnerships: Adopting to Change, 2008 (Box-folder 2/4)
- Developing Funding Collaboratives to Support Workforce Partnerships, Unknown (Box-folder 2/5)
- Greener Pathways, 2008 (Box-folder 2/6)
- Starting Over... A Survival Guide for Laid-off Workers and their Families, 2001 (Box-folder 2/7)
- Workforce and Economic Development, Unknown (Box-folder 2/8)
- Los Angeles Health Care Workforce, 2008 (Box-folder 2/9)
- Worker Education & Resource Center, Inc., Unknown (Box-folder 2/10)
- Advance Program, Unknown (Box-folder 2/11)
- Contra Costa Times, 2008 March 24 (Box-folder 2/12)
- Healthcare Career Advancement Academy Bridge Training Program, Unknown (Box-folder 2/13)
- LATTC - Utilities and Construction Preparation, Unknown (Box-folder 2/14)
- California Commission for Economic Development, Unknown (Box-folder 2/15)
- California's Edge - Keeping California Competitive Creating Opportunity, Unknown (Box-folder 2/16)
- America's Forgotten Middle-Skill Jobs, 2007 November (Box-folder 2/17)
- Green-Collar Jobs in America's Cities, 2008 (Box-folder 2/18)
- A Greener Future for Los Angeles, 2008 April (Box-folder 2/19)
- America's Forgotten Middle-Skill Jobs, 2007 November (Box-folder 2/20)
- Building Workforce Partnerships, 2008 June 11-13 (Box-folder 2/21)
- 4th Annual National Labor Program Operators Meeting, 2008 June 10 (Box-folder 2/22)
- Global Sweatshop Curriculum Packet, 1997 (Box-folder 2/23)
- Communities @ Work - A Guide to Restoring Our Right to Organize, Unknown (Box-folder 2/24)
- United for a Fair Economy -- Tax Reform -- Train the Trainer, Unknown (Box-folder 2/25)
- Common Sense Economics, Unknown (Box-folder 2/26)
- Newsletters, clippings and unpublished papers, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 3/1)
- School to Work Training, 1997 October (Box-folder 3/2)
- Fourth Annual Summer School for Trade Union Women [1 of 2], 1990 (Box-folder 3/3)
- Fourth Annual Summer School for Trade Union Women [2 of 2], 1990 (Box-folder 3/4)
- Bargaining for Power: A Teaching Manual for Staff and Local Union Bargaining Committees, Unknown (Box-folder 3/5)
- Interest-Based Neogtiation -- Participant's Guidebook, Unknown (Box-folder 3/6)
- Contract Campaign Manual: Service Employees International Union AFL-CIO, CLC, Unknown (Box-folder 3/7)
- Have Hope Hospital Proposal, 1994 (Box-folder 3/8)
- Misc. Docs from Contract Campaign Manual Binder [1 of 2], Unknown (Box-folder 3/9)
- Misc. Docs from Contract Campaign Manual Binder [2 of 2], Unknown (Box-folder 3/10)
- SEIU International Training Institute, 1990 August 7-9 (Box-folder 3/11)
- Public Sector Bargaining [1 of 2], 1995 April 7-8 (Box-folder 3/12)
- Public Sector Bargaining [2 of 2], 1995 April 7-8 (Box-folder 3/13)
- "Are We Sticking Together or Stuck?" Coalition Building in the 90s, 1990s (Box-folder 3/14)
- CSA Disctrict 925: Grevance Workbooks, Unknown (Box-folder 3/15)
- Reclass Trags [1 of 2], 1991 (Box-folder 3/16)
- Reclass Trags [2 of 2], 1991 March (Box-folder 3/17)
- UW Problem Resolution Plan, 1990 (Box-folder 3/18)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! District 925 SEIU [1 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/19)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [2 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/20)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [3 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/21)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [4 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/22)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [5 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/23)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [6 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/24)
- 1st Class Staff, 1st Class Contract! Disctrict 925 SEIU [7 of 7], Unknown (Box-folder 3/25)
- Union posters, 1990, 2017 (Box-folder OSVF0194)
  "Our Power is Our Contract," 1990, SEIU; "Dia de los Muertos," 2017, OPEIU Local 8; "Proud to be an office worker/ Proud to be Union," 1990, SEIU